Dennis Mai

Full Stack Web Developer



dmai.developer@gmail.com



🗎 Lihue, HI 96766



(469) - 785 - 2133

Freelance and Contract Web Developer, committed to improving business outcomes. I utilize my experience in business, education and programming to distill problems to their essence, collaborate with my team, and provide simple, powerful solutions with technology. I am fluent in the MERN stack and have a keen eye for crafting user-centered experiences and designs.

Experience

Freelance Web Developer & Contractor

Self-Employed — Lihue, HI

08/2018 - Present

- Strategically create and market digital campaigns for businesses and individuals
- Budget, scope, and plan projects with clear deliverables, timelines, & responsibilities
- Continuously communicate and collaborate with stakeholders while developing technical solutions
- + Achievements:
 - Prototyped Quiz app UI (https://www.triviaquizgame.com not maintained) using PHP, Tailwind & Javascript
 - Revised proprietary crawlers for https://www.collegeconsensus.com/ using Puppeteer in Node.js

Business Analyst — Inventory Specialist

DeinDeal AG - Zurich, Switzerland

06/2014 - 11/2016

- Orchestrate complex operations between multiple departments for major online events and inventory management
- Gather, clean, and process raw data to optimize purchasing & sales decisions for sales potential vs. financial risk
- + Tasked with improving Inventory Turnover from 7 months to industry-appropriate benchmarks. Spear-headed major online sales events, analyzed pricing & product lifecycles, and coordinated with other departments. Drastically reduced Inventory Turnover to 3-5 months within 2 months of implementation and re-defined company category management.

Skills

+ Frameworks & Libraries:

React, Redux, Apollo Client, Bootstrap, Express, Styled-Components, Tailwind

+ Scripting Languages:

Javascript ES5+, Typescript, Node.js, Python3

+ Testing & Deployment:

Webpack, Babel, Gulp, Jest, Enzyme, React Testing Library, Heroku, Netlify

+ Markup & Style:

HTML5, Markup, ejs, CSS3, SCSS

+ Databases:

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, GraphQL, mySQL, Redis

+ Design Tools:

Adobe XD, Figma, Zeplin, Inkscape

+ Collaboration & Productivity:

Git, Github, Bitbucket, Slack, Jira, Salesforce, Google Suite

Language & Education

Natural Languages

Fluent Written & Verbal: English, French, Spanish Conversational: Swiss-German, German, Vietnamese

Education

Wichita State University - 2007-2012 **BBA Economics** 3.9 GPA 3.8 GPA **BA Spanish**